<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Opinion on Securing The Net</title>
    <link>https://securingthe.net/categories/opinion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Opinion on Securing The Net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 20:16:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://securingthe.net/categories/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Common question: What certs should I get?</title>
      <link>https://securingthe.net/2019/common-question-what-certs-should-i-get/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 20:16:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://securingthe.net/2019/common-question-what-certs-should-i-get/</guid>
      <description>I recently had a discussion around certifications with one of the people I&amp;rsquo;m mentoring, and thought it might be worth summarizing here. Certs can often be a polarizing topic in the information security world, so let me preface this post by very clearly stating my opinion about certs:
I believe certs are a great way to get past HR filters or to send certain signals to a hiring manager, but are not necessarily indicative of (or a replacement for) hands-on experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>InfoSec is Bigger Than Pentesting</title>
      <link>https://securingthe.net/2018/infosec-is-bigger-than-pentesting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 12:36:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://securingthe.net/2018/infosec-is-bigger-than-pentesting/</guid>
      <description>So far this year I&amp;rsquo;ve interviewed several candidates for a security analyst position. It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty straightforward blue team role involving things like vulnerability assessment and remediation, identifying anomalies in user or system activity, and some internal audit functions. Unfortunately most of the candidates I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered are only interested in pure pentesting jobs.
The cool kids table I get it, red team has all the fun right? Writing exploits, popping shells, they&amp;rsquo;re the Top Gun pilots of infosec.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>